vrefpub.com 2019-09-13

# VREF Privacy Policy | VREF Aircraft Value Reference

### Privacy Policy

Thank you for visiting the VREF website. Here, you can learn how VREF uses the personal information collected at this site. Please read this privacy policy before using the site or submitting any personal information. Using the site means you are accepting the practices described in this privacy policy. We may change these practices, but we will post any changes. What’s more, changes will only apply to activities and information going forward, not retroactively. We encourage you to review the privacy policy whenever you visit VREF site to make sure that you understand how any personal information you provide will be used. Note: the privacy practices set forth in this privacy policy are for this website only. Please review the privacy policies posted at any other websites you may link to.

### Collection of Information

When you visit Vref.com, Vrefonline.com or Vrefpub.com you may voluntarily submit personally identifiable information such as your name, postal address, email address(es) and phone numbers; credit/debit card numbers, expiration date and other billing information; people to whom purchases will be shipped, including addresses and phone numbers; and purchase history. We use this information only to fulfill your specific request, unless you give us permission to use it in another manner. An example might be using your personally identifiable information to add you to one of our mailing lists.

### Cookie/Tracking Technology

At  Vref.com, Vrefonline.com or Vrefpub.com we may use cookie and tracking technology depending on the features offered. These technologies are useful for determining information such as the type of device you accessed the site on (computer, mobile phone or other device), the browser type and operating system, tracking the number of visitors to Vref.com, Vrefonline.com or Vrefpub.com, and understanding how visitors use the site. We may also track the URL you just came from, which URL you go to next, and your Internet Protocol (IP) address, as well as the date and time you visited.

Other examples of information we may collect are purchase history, what pages you viewed or terms you searched for, visits to certain pages and page interaction information.

Using cookies, we can customize the site for visitors. We cannot collect personal information using cookies and other tracking technology. However, cookies may be tied to any personally identifiable information that you previously provided. We may share aggregate cookie and tracking information with third parties. To prevent your browser from accepting new cookies or to disable cookies altogether, go to the Help feature on your browser.

### Mobile Devices

We may collect certain additional information if you use a mobile device to access our site. This may include information about your location, a unique identifier for the device, its mobile operating system and the type of mobile Internet browser that you use. We may use this information to provide you with location-based services and information, such as advertising, search results, and other personalized content. Your device will most likely allow you to disable location services. Additionally, you can opt out of Google Ad Settings for mobile apps. If you have questions about this, contact your mobile service carrier or the device manufacturer.

### Distribution of Information

It is our policy at VREF not to use or share your information in ways unrelated to those described above. There is an exception, however: we may share information with governmental agencies or other companies assisting us in fraud prevention or investigation. We may do so when: (1) permitted or required by law; or, (2) trying to protect against or prevent actual or potential fraud or unauthorized transactions; or, (3) investigating fraud which has already taken place. Under these circumstances, the information is not provided to these companies for marketing purposes.

### Retargeting

VREF uses Google and other third party ad networks to manage our advertising on other sites. Using cookies and web beacons, our ad network partner collects non-personally identifiable information about your activities on Vref.com, Vrefonline.com or Vrefpub.com and other websites. This information is used to provide targeted advertising based upon your interests.

### Google Analytics Advertising Features

We have enabled Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting for this site. This means that we are allowing Google Analytics to collect data about this site’s traffic via Google advertising cookies and anonymous identifiers. Google is also collecting data through standard Google Analytics implementation, including tracking codes, Google Analytics SDK, and the Measurement Protocol.

You can opt out of these Google Analytics Advertising Features through Ads Settings, or through the NAI’s consumer opt-out.

### Commitment to Data Security

Please be assured that we keep your personally identifiable information secure. Only authorized employees, agents and contractors, who have agreed to keep information secure and confidential, have access to this information. We use firewalls, systems and procedures to protect the security of your personal information. If you have entered credit card information on our site, we have encrypted it. You have the ability to opt out of further emails and newsletters from this site.

### Privacy Contact Information

If you have any questions, concerns, or comments about our privacy policy, please contact us at:

VREF Publishing, Inc.  
PO BOX 57295  
Des Moines, IA 50317  

VREF reserves the right to make changes to this policy. Any changes to this policy will be posted on this website.
